<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-civil-war-secessions</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83035143/1861-04-10/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The Times correspondent reiterates lliat an
attempt wiilbe made to provision Sumter by an
armed vessel. Special to the Evening Port. It le reported
from Charleston to-day that I.ieut. Talbot ha
not been permitted to return to Fort Sumter.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026965/1861-04-11/ed-1/seq-2//</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Temperance of South Carolina will meet
at Sumter, on Wednesday, the 24th of
April, at seven o'clock, p. m.
Judge Marvin, of Key West, who has
heretofore pronounced-himself a citLzon of
tho United States, has lately declared for
the Confederate States.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83025725/1861-04-11/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Peace is Union, life, prosperity war is
disunion, strife, dissolution, death. What
' are Sumter and Pickens in a question of such
magnitude ? What can the Federal adminis
tration gain by holding them for a few weeks
or for a few months? Can it thereby enforce
any law ? Can it collect any revenue ? Can
it bring back the seceded States to the Union,
and restore brotherhood and confraternity ?
Can it benefit a partizan administration, or
the citizens of the country ? Can the Federal
Government, by holding these Forts over
power the "Confederate States," and reduce
them to the condition of subject provinces,
if that be the policy ? Is any of these ends
to be reached by holding Sumter and Pick
ens ? Who is so obtuse as to believe it?
The theory of the seceded States is that
these forts belong to them, and that their oc
cupation by an authority which they do not
recognise, is an act of hostility in itself.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87076793/1861-04-12/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>immediate evacuation of Fort Sumter,
Gentlemen. Next, we rei'iiiro yon to
evr.t uate New Mexico. Ariinna, snd the
Indian Territory, and quit-claim them tJ
the Coiif'tderncv.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87076766/1861-04-13/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Iy these despatches it will be seen that the treason which has so
long been rife at Charleston, has at last culminated in WAR ! The
rebels will now be treated in a different manner than they anticipa
ted. They have brought down vengeance on their own heads. The
country waits with breathless anxiety to, know the result of this at
tack. We believe the Government is sufficient for the emergency.
Without further remarks we give the despatches:
Charleston, April 12th. The following is the
telegraphic correspondence between the War
Department at Montgomery and Oen. Beaure
gard immediately preceding the hostilities. The
c orrefrpondence grew out of the formal notifica
tion by the Washington Government which is
disclosed in Oen. Beauregard's first dispatches:
No.1. Charleston, April 8th, 1861.
L. T. Walkkb, Secretary of War: An au
thorized inotwvnger from President Lincoln just
informed Gov. Pickens and mysell that provis
ions will be sent to Fort Sumter peaceably, or
otherw ise by force. Signed,
G. T. BEAUREGARD.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045160/1861-04-14/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Our dispatch by telegraph this '.morning
from Fort Sumter are of thrilling intereat.
After a protracted cannonading and bombard
ment of tbirty-fve boars by tba Confederate
troops, Andersen's garrison capitulated about
three o'clock r. at. on yesterday, and .the
Southern flag now wave in Moodiest trlampb
from its ramparts I Federal war veaaela made
their appearance off the barber during the con
flict, and participated in tb return of fire from
Fort Sumter. There can be ao doubt of the
fact of the surrender, a a private dispatch . re
ceived from Secretary Walker by a gentlemst
n tbe city, published in another roluma, amply
corroberatea it. Aa we predicted mors than a
month ago, the aaglea of victory have parched
upon tbe Southern standard In tbe first real
battle of tbe "IaaaranaiaLK Coxvlict."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82014760/1861-04-15/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>By the President of the United States :
A PROCLAMATION.
Whereas the laws of the United States have
been for tome time past, and now are, opposed,
and the execution thereof obstructed, in the
States of South Carolina, Georgia, Alabama,
Florida, Mississippi, Louisiana, and Texas, by
combinations too powerful to be suppressed by
the ordinary course of judicial proceeding, or
by the powers vested in the marshals by law :
Now, therefore, I, Abhahim Lixcolv, Presi
dent of the United States, in virtue of tho
power in me vested by the Constitution and the
laws, have thought fit to call forth, and do
hereby call forth, the militia of the several
States of tho United States of the Union, to the
aggregate number of seventy-five thousand, in
order to suppress said combinations, and to
cause the laws to be duly executed. ... The delay in the arrival of the" fleet nt
Charleston, which resulted from the storm, was
most opportune for the rebels, although, under
the circumstances of the short resistance made
by Fort Sumter, it did not probably change the
issue of stents.
Maryland. This State, according to all re
liable reports received here, is sound to the
core. If wanted, 10,000 men could bo raised
in Maryland in twenty four hours, to assist in
avenging the capture of Fort Sumter.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030213/1861-04-15/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>He approarhed a portliole and was met by
Maj. Anderaon. Tbe coinuiander of Fort Sumter said
he bad juat diBpluyed a white tlag, but tbe tiring from
the Care-lina buitcrie* wua kept up, neverthcleea.
Col. Wigfall replied that Muj. Anderaon muat bi.ul
duwn tbe Aoieriean flag; thal no parley would be
granted. Surrender or light waa the word. Maj. An
dur-on then hauled down hia finp;, and diflplaved only
tbat of tnice.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83025725/1861-04-16/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>They have captured Fort
Sumter, which has been pionounced the
ctmnTPstFort in America. They had the
advantage and did their work with ease.-
This we consider entirely sufficient to con
vince the Administration that the Confeder
ate States are not playing a ridiculous farce
to amuse the rest of mankind, but, if forced
to carry out the programme they have al
ready determined upon and published, the
denouement will inevitably be a most serious
and real tragedy. </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84028385/1861-04-17/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Civil War Begun—Fort Sumter Taken.
The traitors and rebel? yi the'eotton
States, not content with talking, rebellion,
going through the farce of organising a go
YernmeB and enacting laws on poper,
stealing public ttoney and property, taking
aseaaU and forts, through - the treicLcry
and fraud of government officials, bat em
boldened by thcitToeeess in these attempt
they Late at last culminated their treason
by levying open war againf t their country
and its Government, attacked " end taken
by force of arms, a United States Fort...</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026965/1861-04-17/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Fort .Sumter,
and this morning the gun-battcrries re?
opened lire, to which Anderson replied
vigorously at 7 o'clock. At 8 a. m. smoke
was seen issuing from the parapet roof of
Sumter. Barracks set on tiro by hot shot
or shell. During the fire three explosions of com?
bustibles occurred in the fort.
About 1 o'clock, the United States flag?
staff M as shot away. Wigfall approach?
ed from Moms' Island with a win to flag,
entered and stated ho was Aid of Beaurc?
gard, that seeing his distress he claim?
ed, in the name of his'Chiof, a surrender,
In reply to the inquiry, what terms would
be granted? he stated that Bean regard
was a soldier and a gentleman, and knew
how to treat a gallant enemy, but Ander?
son could not make bis own terms, and
must leave details to Be an regard.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026399/1861-04-18/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Fire opened on Fori Sumter. Anderson
reluming tltc Fire The Fori inflames
Its guns silenced Surrender of Hi
Fort and Garrison Tic Port of
Cluirleiton to be blockaded Rebel State
Mail to be withdrawn TheGarrison
aoins to New York 75.000 Militia
called for An extra session of Congress
Charleston, Firday, April 12, 1801.
Gifil war has at last begun. A terri
ble fight is at this moment going on be
tweeu Fort Sumter aud tho fortification
by which it is surrouuded.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85054845/1861-04-18/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>WAR BEGUN !
THE TRAITORS FIRE THE FIRST GUN!
FORT SUMTER .ITTACILKD !
Anderson Returns tke Fire !
SUMTER'S WALL BREACHED !
THE FORT IN FLAMES I ITS GUNS SILENCED !
Surrender of tlie Fort and Gar
rison !
NOT A LIFE LOST IX THE CONFLICT.
MAJOR ANDERSON AND HIS COMMAND
EMBARK FOR NEW YORK.
THE PORT of CHARLESTON BLOCKADED.
FORT PICKENS RE-ENFORCED.
Tlie President's Proclamation.
75,000 VOLUNTEERS WANTED!
AC, AC, AC.
The War has been .commenced ! The
blow which we have been awaiting, but
which we would fain have averted, has
fallen ! The so-called Southern Confed
eracy has plunged tho country into a war
that must be, indeed, terrible; ior it will
be the death-struggle between Freedom
and Slavery.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86053832/1861-04-20/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>WAR_ BEGUN!
FORT SUMIPTER
TAI.ZE W 0F1ýT
Plaquemine, Saturday Morning 13th.
Our obliging postmaster has just fur
nished us with the Evening Delta of
yesterday, containing the following im
portant news. We shall condense it
all we can, without leaving out any im
portant items.
There is a despatsh fromMontgomery,
stating that Gen. Beauregard opened
his fire on Fort Sumpter yesterday
morning at 4 o'clock.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83016751/1861-01-11/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>—lt is universally conceded that Major
Anderson acted wisely in evacuating Fort
Moultrie, and occupying Fort Sumpter.
Military men at the east, are in extacies
over the movement, and it is only objected
to by the secessionists. It is conceded that
it would require a continuous bombardment
of six months with guns of the heaviest
metal to destroy Fort Sumpter, and then it
coaid only be done, if at all, by chipping off
the masonry piece by piece; The New
York Herald gives the best sketch we have
seen of Fort Sumpter:
Fort Sumpter is one of the most powerful
military works in the United States. </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82005159/1861-07-12/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>PRESIDENT'S MESSIGE.
Fellow-Citizens of the Senate
and of the House of Representatives :
Having been convened on an extraordinary
occasion, authorized by the Constitution, your
attention is not called to an ordinary subject of
legislation.
At the beginning ol the present Presidential
term, four months ago, the functions of the Fed
eral Government were found to be generally
suspended within the several States of'South
Carolina, Georgia, Alabama, Mississippi, Lou
isiana and Florida, excepting those onlv of the
Post office Department.
Within these States all the forts, arsenals,
dockyards, custom-houses, and the like, inclu
ding the movable and stationary property in
and about them, had been seized and held in o
pen hostility to this Government, excepting on
ly Forts Pickens, Taylor and Jefferson, on and
near the Florida coast, and Fort Sumpter, in
Charleston Harbor, South Carolina.
The forts thus seized had b-en put in impro
ved condition, new ones had been built, and ar
med forces had been organized, and were orga
nizing, all avowedly with the same hostile pur
pose. The forts remaining in the possession of
the Federal Government in and near these
Sfatps were either besieged or menaced by war
like preparations, and especially Fort Sumpter
was nearly surrounded by well protected hos
tile batteries, with guns equal in quality to the
best of its own, and outnumbering the fatter,
perhans, two to one.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83016751/1861-04-19/ed-1/seq-8/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>General Beauregard at two o’clock to-day
demanded the surrender of Fort Sumpter,
which Major Anderson declined. It is
currently reported that negotiations relative
to the surrender will be opened to-morrow
between Anderson and Beauregard.
Special despatches received at Washing
ton to-day assert that both Pickens and
Sumpter will be attacked, but they doubt
if war follows.
A Montgomery despatch to-day says it
has been resolved to attack the two forts
immediately.
Three steamers were seen off the coast
yesterday for a long time. Anderson fired
a signal gun this morning. The attack of
Fort Sumpter is momentarily expected.
Business is suspended. It is rumored that
the fight will commence at eight o’clock
this evening, unless Major Anderson sur
renders.
The steamer Harriet Lane is off the bar.
Thousands of persons are lining the shores
to witness the attack.
Charleston, April 12.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85025569/1861-04-17/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Fort Sumpter surrendered yesterday,
Beauregard and three fire companies went
to it and extinguished the fire before it
reached the magazine. The Fort was
burned to a mere shell. The walls were
like honey comb. Anderson delivered up
his sword to Wiglall who returned it to him,
a war thirty
vessel to-morrow. Tho fleet lay by
.1 ,, hours, and could nott orw
would not come to
ed, some of them split, All the barracks
and quarters burned down, and the walls
burned and blackened and knocked into
honey comb. Fort Moultrie is badly dam
agee, aud the houses no Morris Island were
completely riddled. The floating battery
North! proved impcnatrable, ever shot from it
told on Fort Sumpter.
WASHINGTON, April, 14 1S61.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83016751/1861-04-19/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>FORT SUMPTER.
A Description of the Fort—the Garri
son—the Floating Battery-—the
South Carolina Forces.
The news of the contest at Charleston,
and the surrender of Fort Sumpter, gives
special interest to a description of that post.
The Herald of the 10th, has a lengthy arti
cle, from which we quote the following ex
tracts :
FORT SUMPTER.
Fort Sumpter is a modern truncated pen
tagonal fort, built upon an artificial island
at the mouth of Charleston harbor, three
and tbree-eigth miles from the city of
Charleston. The island has for its base a
sand and mud bank, with a superstructure,
if we may so term it, of the refuse chips
from several northern granite quarries.
These rocks are firmly imbedded in the sand,
and upon them the present fortification is
reared. The island itself cost half a mil
lion dollars, and was ten years in construc
tion- The fortification cost another half a
million dollars, and at the time of its occu
pancy by Major Anderson was so nearly
completed as to admit the introduction of
its armament...</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83016751/1861-10-25/ed-1/seq-9/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Six months ago last Saturday the great
conspiracy of the .Southern Sluveoeracy
blossomed into actual rebellion by the
opening demonstration of war at Fort
Sumpter.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84020422/1861-02-07/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87090585/1861-01-18/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Charleston, January 14.
The Legislature passed resolutions to-day ap
proving the act of firing into the steamship Star
of the West, and declaring that any attempt to
reinforce Fort Sumpter will be regarded as a de
claration of war.
Gov. I’ickcns invites trading vessels to Ckales
ton, assuring them that none will be disturbed,
unless bearing taoops or munitions of war to
Fort Sumpter.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82015408/1861-02-23/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The steamer Star of the West had been chartered by
the Federal Government to carry a reinforcement of
troups to Fort Sumpter, S. C. On entering the harbor
she was fired into by the South Carolinians from
Morris Wand and Fort Moultrie, and obliged to stand
out to sea and go back. The excitement which this
first shot had created throughout the Union was in
tense. The seceeding states are now : South Carolina, Ala
bama, Louisiana and Mississippi.
Secretary Kelly has resolved to remove all clerks
from the Interior Department who are found to be
sec-ssionists.
Missouri Senators will make formal protest against
the occupation of public buildings at St Louis by
Federal troop. .
The following dispatch hs been received by U. C.
Limar, President of the Baifk of the ltepublic :
Cha M.E8TON , Jan. 14th. Sir Please have it au
thoritatively published that no fl g and no vessel will
be disturbed or prevented from entering our haibor,
unless bearing hostile troops or munitions of war for
Fort Sumpter. All trade is desired, and all vessels of
commerce will be gladly received.
Signed.W. Pickens.
Judge Smally, of the U. S. Circuit Court, in his
chnrge'to the Grand Jury to-day, declared South Car
olina guilty of high treson
harlesto!. Jan. 14. Resolutions have unani
mously passed the Legislature, declaring that any at
tempt by the Federal Government to reinforce Fort
Sumpter, will be regarded as an act of open hostility
and a declaration of war; also approving of the act
and promptness of the military in firing on the Star of
the West, and promising to support the government in
all measures of defense.</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-cherry-blossom-trees</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042462/1909-10-19/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>MANY CHERRY TREES
SHIPPED BY MIKADO
JAPAN SENDS U. S. OVER 2000
FINE SPECIMENS -
Many Saplings from Orient Will B«
Planted Along Potomac and Riv
erside Driveways — Mrs.
Taft Recipient
WASHINGTON, Oct. 18.—When tha
honorary commercial commissioners of
Japan arrives in Washington, Novem
ber 1, they will be taken on an auto
mobile ride which will include Poto
mac drive, along which 2000 cherry
trees to be presented to this country
by the emperor of Japan are to be
planted.
The shipment of the trees and the
planting thereof have been entrusted
to Toraklro Watase, proprietor of a
Tokio plant and seed company, who
is one of the commissioners.
Speaking of the gift of the emperor
to the city of Washington, Mr. Watase
said the trees would be sent to Mrs.
Taft, wife of the president, and by
her presented to the government for
transplanting- along- Potomac drive.
Former President Roosevelt and
President Taft are chiefly responsible
for the improvement of the Potomac
river front, and it was Mrs. Taft ivho
gave the name Potomac park to that
section of the city. She made popular
the afternoon promenades on the drive,
which were a feature last year of
summer life in the capital.
New York Remembered
The emperor of Japan Is sending to
New York also a large number of
cherry trees to be planted along River
side drive and Grant's tomb.
In Japan, the land of the cherry
blossom, there are many beautiful
legends about the trees and flower of
the cherry.
The blossom of the Japanese cherry
is of a peculiarly delicate beauty, and
there is a tradition in Japan that if
that same tone appears in the blos
soms of the Japanese cherry planted
in another country, that country can
he taken and subjugated by Japan.
Mr. Watase is authority for the
statement that while many Japanese
cherry trees have been brought to the
United States, the color of the bloa
eoms, although just as beautiful, is
unlike the blossom which appears in
Japan.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82016187/1909-12-23/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Our new Potomac Park down beyond
the monument is to be beautified by
Japanese cherry trees Col Cosby Su
perintendent of Public Buildings and
Grounds has been informed by Jukio
OzakI the Mayor of Tokyo Japan that
the 2000 cherry trees which were pre
sented to the city of Washington have
arrived at Seattle and will be shipped
at once to this city Tho Mayor of
Tokyo said in his letter It gives me
great pleasure to inform you that the
corporation of Tokyo at a recent meet
ing of its Councils resolved to present
2000 Japanese cherry trees to the Gov
ernment of the United States for tho
use of the city of Washington And
the Mayor goes on to say The cherry
trees are extensively cultivated in this
country and are the most admired of
the flowering trees Ten of the most
representative kinds have been selected
and I beg to assure you that it will re
main to the citizens of Tokyo a pleas
ing memory as well as a matter of civic
pride to know that their small offering
will be permitted to contribute to the
advancement of the beautiful Capital
of the great Republic which they all
admire</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86069675/1910-01-19/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>...japanese < Cherry Trees Present
ed Mrs Taft
The Emperor of Japans re
membrance of President Taft s
great enjoyment of the cherry >
blossom festival season when in i
Japan has taken the graceful form
of the presentation to Mrs Taft
of three car loads of young < cherry
trees and they are now in Wash
ington
The greatest care bas been tekeen
all the way from the land of the
Mikado to keep the iemperature
an uneven stage that the trees
Tuftns i
in apprpciutiou < > tile oppuntunity
for a cherry blossom</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1910-01-29/ed-1/seq-6/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>TO DESTROY JAPANESE TREES.
Gifts from Tokio to Wasnington Found
To Be Badly Diseased.
Washington, Jan. 2S.— Regret has been
expressed by the President and by Mrs.
Taft because two thousand Japanese
cherry trees presented b> the municipality
of Toklo to this government for use In the
national capita' have been found to be
Ir.fected with root gall worms, certain dis
eases and Insect pests, some of the latter
hitherto unknown in this country. The
trees were to have been planted in Poto
m;\c Park, wl^.ich Mrs. Taft did much last
year to have made the outdoor boulevard
and meeting place of social \\ ashington.
The Secretar of Agriculture s.,- .m
It necessary to recommend the destruc
tion of the trees. Secretary Knox lias ex
ptm ■ i to the Japanese Ambassador the
regret of the government authorities that
the gift cannot be used, and Colonel Cosby,
in charge of Public Building" and Grounds,
has conveyed reyrets to the Mayor of
Toklo.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045433/1910-10-16/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Mikados prfv prtwy coiprH and aMoUter frsM d dother moss mossother
other distingtsW dlsUn ir dtce Lces LcesAs losv losvAs
As a nsarfc inarc ofWiear t rrIeHM le sira a ir Ofsdc Ofsdcsent 0 baent Onkesent
sent 1008 1 cherry trees to 1IhW Mrs w Taft re recently fttenth atcently ¬
cently but they became came Infected and did didnot didnot didnot
not live live</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82016187/1910-12-22/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>It will be remembered that tho Em
peror of Japan last Spring sent several
thousand Japanese cherry trees to Mrs
Taft to be placed along the Iotomac
Drive which she originated These
cherry trees were found to be infected
witha peculiar injurious Japanese in
sect and for fear they would contami
nate the cherry trees In this country
the whole lot was burned It is now
announced that the Japanese authori
ties are sending another consignment
of cherrj trees that have been exam
ined and shown to be clear of all dis
ease Mrs Taft has on numerous occa
sions been honored by the Japanese
Government In the White House thero
is a magnificent and well nigh priceless
cabinet of Japanese lacquer inlaid with
gold which was presented to Mrs Taft
by the Empress of Japan when she
was abroad with President Taft In
the cabinet are also two unique vases
in silver containing bouquets of silver
flowers She was also presented with
a number of Japanese dolls that are
cutely attractive and also very valua
ble...</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1912-03-06/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>CHERRY TREES ON THE WAY
Long Delayed ?Tapanese Gift to
City Soon to Arrive.
Th? long looked for chfrry trees which
the Japanese government offered to ?ara?
sent to this city a! th. tin-.c of the b?ud?
Pulton celebration will be here in a
few days Tho consignment, which In?
trudes 2,100 y??ung cherrv tr?es, ar?
rived last week in Seattle, and is now be?
ing shipped to this city oveT th? Great
Northern Railroad.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045433/1912-03-28/ed-1/seq-12/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>JAPANESE TREES IS TOPIC.
Miss E. It. Scldntore o Address
tlounl Geographic Society.
Descriptions of a variety of Japanese
trees, which have Just been received In
Washington and are to be planted In Po
tomac Park, will be given by Mies E. R.
Scldmore. who Is to address the National
Geographic Society to morrow at 4 15
o clock and again at 8 IS o'clock at New
Masonic Temple.
Her subject will be "Japanese gar
dens," an exposition of the theories and
rules of Japanese landscape gardening
The lecture will be illustrated wltholor-
ed lantern slides, and Miss Scldmore will
show pictures of .fifty different varieties'
Japanese cherry blossoms Miss
Scldmore. who Is the author of "Jlnrlk
Isha Da j s In Japan." Is an authority on
Japanese life and habits, and It la ex
pected that memDers or tne Japanese
Embassy, as well as many members of
the diplomatic corps, will attend tne
lecture.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1913-04-06/ed-1/seq-10/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>In all the riot of blossoms which hav '
burseohevl forth In Potomac Park wttM
In the last week, to make that tract
the, most gorgeous anywhere la th
jietrict, therr ia none which show morn
delicate beauty than the Moons oa tM
Japenese cherry trees which were ate
rented to the U.iUed States by the gov
-.'rnment of Japan a year ago. TMat
fragrant, beautiful trees are blooratnjjf
Jers for the first time. The river Urle
Yom the Virginia bride up to Twealy
slxtr street la fragrant with them. anA."
thousands have stopped their carriages
to admire the delicacy and beauty Of
the blooms. j. "
Unlike the-domestic cherry tha Ja
3rtrc variety Jeans more to bloom taA
It dos to fruit. The chief strength of
the trees seems-to be spent In pttittrii
foith tha. wonderful clusters of .blos
soms which cover the'llmbs. The tries .
have been plinttd for just a little mora
Uvan a year and of course have hot
obtained any beauty in regard to c3
roimation. The pruning kalfe hast pkk
opportunity to work toward symetry
and the branches spread awkwariiy
aioe the main stem.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1919-04-07/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Japan has come to the United
States Just a little bit of the Flowery
Kingdom, to be sure tmt enough to
make even the most unimaginative
person long to see "cherry felosjoa
time In Nippon.
Down at the Tidal Basin, the other
side of the Monument, a galaxy of
Japanese cherry trees are Is full and
fragrant bloom blooms that are try
Ing to say with U. their delicate
pinkness and sweetness that -spring
Is here, that they live "but to weave
garlands for her costumes and
wreath lor her hair.
Yesterday every member of the
Japanese embassy made a pilgrimage
to the- cherry trees from their own
far-away country stood In wonder
and delight at the sight of the flowers
they love so well. It was like being
transported "back to Japan for a few
happy moments, they said.
But it's only a sample of what
Japan really looks like, they declare,
for In their country the trees are tea
times as big as our trees, although
not a whit lovelier, for the climate
here Is ideal for the full flowering of
the- Japanese trees...</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1921-03-27/ed-1/seq-61/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>A FEATURE of unique beauty
which distinguishes Washington
and Potomac Park over all cities
and parks in this country is the ;
how of Japanese cherry blossoms. No j
other city or park has anything comparable
to or approaching the great !
masses, the clouds and billows of nale
pink flowers that surround the Tidal
Basin and border all the river front,..</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1956-04-08/ed-1/seq-160/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>F THE WASHINGTON STAR • WASHINGTON, D. C. • APRIL 8, 1956
CHERRY BLOSSOM TIME if
The Democratic Party</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1962-04-03/ed-1/seq-29/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1953-03-25/ed-1/seq-30/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90059523/1904-04-03/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE SPRING FESTIVAL OF THE CHERRY BLOSSOM
Shikishima no
Yamato-gokoro wo
Hito towaba,
Asa-hi ni niou
Yama-zakura-bana.
— From the poems of Motoori.
AND the verses here printed, be
ing translated, tell:
"If one should in
quire of you concern
ing the spirit of a true Japanese,
point to the wild cherry blossom
shining in the sun."
Another Japanese proverb says:
"The cherry blossom is first among
flowers as the warrior is first
among men." The cherry blos
som is in Japan what the rose
is in England and the thistle in
Scotland. Practically it is worshipped
as the essential spirit of the goddess
of beauty and truth and loyalty to men
and country. </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1958-03-16/ed-1/seq-73/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Georgia's Cherry Blossom princess, Miss
Isabelle Collier, chats on the balcony of the new House Office Building
with Representative James C. Davis of Georgia, who will act as her escort
during the festival luncheon.
\ With Mother Nature's co
operation this is the way
the cherry trees will burst
forth at the Tidal Basin for the tradi
tional National Cherry Blossom Festival,
March 25 through 30. A highlight will
be a "Washington Holiday" luncheon
fashion show in the Mayflower Hotel,
at 12:15 p.m., March 27, when Mrs.
Richard Nixon will be guest of honor.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1902-06-29/ed-1/seq-39/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1963-03-31/ed-1/seq-209/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82004649/1916-09-14/ed-1/seq-10/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1955-04-03/ed-1/seq-176/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/10021978/1912-05-01/ed-1/seq-7/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1858-12-06/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Very little attention ia paid to the cultivation
of fmit in this couu'ry Cherry and plnm treea
produce magnificent blossoms, but tney bear very
Uttie fruit; ar.d tbat little is wortbleas. Tbe
p-acbea are far inferior to tboae of China; and tbe
same remark will apply to the apricot.</text>
      </result>
      <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1937-04-08/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Crowds of enthusiastic cherry
blossom admirers were flocking
into the city today from all parts
of the country as the Festival of
the Cherry Blossoms was inaugu
rated officially. The blossoms will reach their
peak over the week-end. It is an
ticipated that this will be the larg
est cherry blossom gathering
Washington has ever seen.
The blossoms were a gift to- this
country from Japan over a score
of years ago. Planted in a scenic
background which complements
their natural beauty, they have be
come one of Washingtons most
famous attractions. Railroads and
busses, taking advantage of their
attraction, have offered cherry
blossom excursions to Washington
for a number of years.</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1897-09-19/ed-1/seq-32/</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84024441/1897-03-04/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn95079490/1897-10-23/ed-1/seq-7/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>It is now possible to cross Tromont
street, Boston, at any point opposite tho
Common and at any time of day without
loss of life or limb. Tho new subway has
brought about tho change.
It 1 s an old tradition that tho fathers of
Boston, when thoy laid out tho city, let
the. streets follow the winding cow paths.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030272/1897-12-15/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The Boston subway ! short. That part now
jkVM tense Is less than ft mile In length, and the
KS farts which are under construction or proposed
R M Would add only about another mile to the tun
Hk wr Bet, There lr, perhaps, no finer specimen of
 passenger tunnel work any whero In the world,
aBfYS n " ls doubtful -f anymore perfect tunnel
HtjH could Deconstructed.
B9p The tunnel runs under Tremont street, and
HHk Its extensions are to go under Cornhlll, Han
JJ. oxer street, and Washington streot, passing
i right through the denso business and shopping
districts...</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82016413/1901-07-24/ed-1/seq-6/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Since
the Boston subway uus completed, a
large part of the population spends Its
time underground, riding back and
forth through the tunnel and exclaim
ing: "Wo did It!
This has Increased the above-ground '
Inhabitants to so small a number that
It's a good time to oercomo public
opinion, because there's so little of It
to overcome. Consequently thd Boston
women refeired to t:nn seized the
chance to establish the new fad In rid
ing. They Know that by the tlmo the
people get tired ut looking nt their hole
In the ground, bloomers will nave be
come a pait of thfl Boston eieed of B's.
Its growing. </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1903-06-21/ed-1/seq-42/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84020274/1904-05-08/ed-1/seq-57/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88085947/1904-10-27/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88085947/1904-10-27/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87060004/1905-01-19/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>ANOTHER BOSTON SUBWAY
Eat Ilpnlon Tunnel Junt Openti
IllliiM Under Itnrbor
Boston the pioneer city of America
In subway construction now boasts a
subway Maid to be the greatest single
boring yet completed under the enter
of a river or harbor It Is tho EnSt
Boston tiinnl extending from tile
zing UA8T JtOSTON TUNNEL
city proper under the harbor to
Maverick square East Boston It Is
the second subway to be opened In
Boston wns begun In 1000 has cost
3000000 and has Just been turned
over to tint Boston EIu rated Rallwny
company for operation It Id about
one ones twofifth miles In length and
has an exterior diameter of nearly
thirty feet thoilgli the thickness of
the walls bring Its Interior diameter
down to about twentyfour feet
The East Boston tunnel nets to n
depth of more than ninety feet below
tho waters of Boston harbor through
n blue day sediment It Is fov the
use of regulntlpn trolley cars which
come to the surface at the suburban
end of tilt passage nnd continue their
Journeys over tliestrce trucks</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87078082/1910-12-07/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1912-06-07/ed-1/seq-30/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BOSTON'S SUBWAY, SURFACE AND ELEVATED LINES
PRACTICALLY TIED UP BY STRIKE
Boston, June 7. By noon to
day the surface, elevated and sub
way car system of Boston and
suburbs was utterly disorganized.
A strike of the union employes
of the Boston Elevated, which
controls the surface and subway
lines, was called at 4:15 o'clock
this morning after a stormy three
hour session at union headquar
ters. The elevated officials laughed
at the strike. When the union was
formed only a few weeks ago the
elevated set about a counter or
ganization, a "protective" asso
ciation they called it.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn97067598/1919-07-21/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>raffic Resumed On Boston
Subway, Elevated And
Surf ace Lines
BOSTON, July 21 Traffic on the surface, ' 'bway
end elevated lines of Greater Boston was resumt oday
after an interruption of f our days caused by tht yike
of Carmen who demanded an eight hour day and l. in
crease in wages. They were granted an eight hou .g. uy
and an increase in wages, the maximum being 62  '-s
an hour. . '</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1919-08-17/ed-1/seq-63/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90005351/1921-12-23/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>EXPLOSION SCARE IN
BOSTON SUBWAY
BOSTON, Dee. 23 Tratìic wa
panilyzed for two hours an !
thousands of commuterà and
Christmas shoppers friplitened in
underground traina when a mr.in
power cable in the Cambridge -''ub-way
prounded and exploded, lhu-5
rhutting ofF the current. Con
fusion broke loose in the vicinity
between Chauncey Street r.nd t'a.
South Station when volume: i f
black smoke poure.d through the
tube and permeateti to adjoin'ii ;
subway systems. The offici:!' o'
the road dcclare that there were
no injuries resulting from the ac
cident. </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn98060035/1900-10-10/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82014086/1920-04-05/ed-1/seq-6/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn89055128/1915-04-03/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>NEW BOSTON SUBWAY OPENS
BOSTON, April 3.—A new subway
section, between the Park street sta
tion and Washington
Dorchester tunnel will be opened to
morrow, principally benefitting the
shopping public.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1912-03-23/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Boston's Subway Opened.
BOSTON, Mass., March 23. The new
subway system for the handling of tho
heavy passenger traffic between Boston
and Cambridge, was formally opened to
day The tunnel, which Is throe and a
quarter miles in length, starts ut tho
Park Street station of the old subway,
and passes under Boston Common,
Beacon Hill, and Charles river to Har
vard bquare ln Cambridge.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn95069780/1906-09-13/ed-1/seq-6/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85038102/1897-09-03/ed-1/seq-7/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn93059165/1906-11-22/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82014248/1897-09-02/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BOSTON'S SUBWAY OPENED.
Electrics Pus Through lor Public Traffic lor
First Time, Sept t.
Boston, Sept. 1.—Part of the subway,
the city's new underground thorough
fare for street cars, was formally
opened to public traffic at 6 oclock,
this morning. The sections which will
be operated for the present are those
under the common and the public gar
den, about three-quarters of a mile' in
length. The other sections are not
completed and will not probably be
opened until next spring.
The subway was begun in March,
1894. The total length of the line is one
and one-half miles and when com
pleted there will be about five miles of
track. The estimated cost of the un
dertaking is $5,500,000, although $7,000,
000 was appropriated by the city of
Boston, which has leased the subway
to the West End Street Railway for a
term of 20 years.
The construction of the subway is the
outcome of years of agitation to re
lieve the traffic on that part of Tre
mont street next the common and
other congested parts of the old section
of the city, where the narrow thor
oughfares become easily obstructed
and are practically impassable at
times.
The route opened, today. Is expected
to greatly relieve street traffic, n
nearly 2,000,000 passengers are carried
pearly on street cars on that part of
Tremont street.
The subway Is 14 feet high, 24 feet
wide where two tracks are laid and 48
feet w ide where there are four tracks.
There are five underground station* at
present and more wtjl be added a* the
work progresses *011 the incomplete sec
tions. The disastrous explosion of gaii
on March 4, last, occurred at the angle
of the sections opened today on the
corner of Tremont and Boylston streets.
Ten people were kille</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn93058748/1897-08-09/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE BOSTON SUBWAY
To Be Open to Traffic on September 1.
Boston, Aug. 8. —The Boston subway
will be opened to public travel on Sep
tember 1; at least, that Is the present
intention of the West End Street Rail
way Company. It is not expected to
have all the details of construction com
pleted at that time, but they will be
sufficiently advanced to warrant the
dedication of the first three sections to
the uses of the electrical transit system.
All the ticket offices and turnstiles at
the foot of the station stairways are
practically completed, and are now be
ing painted to conform with the in
terior finish of the subway.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85038102/1897-08-20/ed-1/seq-7/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
